<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spam Lists on Reusing the wheel</title>
    <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/projects/spam-lists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spam Lists on Reusing the wheel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 15:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://piotr-rusin.github.io/projects/spam-lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in url-shortener</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/12/changes-in-url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 16:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/12/changes-in-url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/08/introducing-my-url-shortener/&#34;&gt;When I introduced my URL shortener project&lt;/a&gt;, I already had a working version and I thought I only needed to improve its front-end to be able to release the first stable version of the application. I also had some ideas for new features to be added to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the longer I looked at my code, the more room for improvements I saw. Although I ended up adding some new features, most of the changes I made since then were refactorizations, changes in design and architecture of the application and code style improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;#8217;m going to describe some of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first stable release of spam-lists</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/11/the-first-stable-release-of-spam-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 10:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/11/the-first-stable-release-of-spam-lists/</guid>
      <description>I released the first stable version of spam-lists. It can be downloaded from github or PyPI.
In comparison to the version described in this post, the stable version contains some changes, mostly spelling error corrections and reformatting of docstrings. I have also changed the license of the project from Apache License 2.0 to MIT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing my URL shortener</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/08/introducing-my-url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 13:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/08/introducing-my-url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;URL addresses can be quite long, mainly because they often consist of path and query components, both containing a number of characters forming names of path segments and values of parameters (not necessarily meaningful to a human reader), or performing other functions. For that reason, they may be hard to type and memorize, or simply aesthetically unpleasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of that, URL shorteners were created. There are plenty of them already, so there is probably no reason to create yet another such application, perhaps with one exception: it seems like an interesting idea for a small programming project that could be later extended with other features. This is why I decided to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/piotr-rusin/url-shortener&#34;&gt;my own URL shortener&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress in development of spam-lists</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/07/progress-in-development-of-spam-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 19:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/07/progress-in-development-of-spam-lists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of my spam-lists library on this blog, I made some progress in its development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reorganized the library a bit, changed the inheritance hierarchy of exception classes, fixed some errors and published the package on PyPI. In this post, I&amp;#8217;m going to describe the changes and explain my reasoning behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam-lists – a host blacklist/whitelist library</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/06/spam-lists--a-host-blacklist/whitelist-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 15:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/2016/06/spam-lists--a-host-blacklist/whitelist-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first project I would like to present on this blog is spam-lists (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/piotr-rusin/spam-lists&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;): a library for querying custom and third party web address blacklists and whitelists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>