<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>refactoring on Reusing the wheel</title>
    <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/tags/refactoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in refactoring on Reusing the wheel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 16:13:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://piotr-rusin.github.io/tags/refactoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Url-shortener: a demo and more refactoring</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/posts/2016-12-31-url-shortener-a-demo-and-more-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 16:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/posts/2016-12-31-url-shortener-a-demo-and-more-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A demo instance of my url-shortener project is now available here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://url-shortener.reusingthewheel.tk/&#34;&gt;https://url-shortener.reusingthewheel.tk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, URL shorteners are deployed under a short domain name (for example: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/&#34;&gt;goo.gl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitly.com/&#34;&gt;bit.ly&lt;/a&gt;). It’s not the case here, but since it’s just a demo I didn’t think looking for a short domain for it was necessary, so I chose a longer domain that is also related to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also made some changes to the application. Some of them were minor, like adjusting font sizes in the front end, renaming some local variables in the back end, etc., but there are also some bigger changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in url-shortener</title>
      <link>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-changes-in-url-shortener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 16:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://piotr-rusin.github.io/posts/2016-12-04-changes-in-url-shortener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://piotr-rusin.github.io/posts/2016-08-05-introducing-my-url-shortener/&#34;&gt;When I introduced my URL shortener project&lt;/a&gt;, I already had a working version and I thought I only needed to improve its front-end to be able to release the first stable version of the application. I also had some ideas for new features to be added to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the longer I looked at my code, the more room for improvements I saw. Although I ended up adding some new features, most of the changes I made since then were refactorizations, changes in design and architecture of the application and code style improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m going to describe some of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>